# YU-CHUN TSENG

Corvallis, OR | (541)740-4037 | yuchun.tseng@oregonstate.edu | linkedin.com/in/yuchuntseng

#### **SUMMARY**

Computer science graduate with academic training in operating system, parallel programming, and data analysis. Six years teaching experience in various software applications plus laboratory management. Awarded for demonstrating remarkable user support and for resolving critical operational issues in previous positions. Provide system administration and back-end development and support in current position.

### **SKILLS**

- Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, Python, C, Haskell, TeX
- Database: PostgreSQL, MySQL
- OS: macOS, Linux, Windows
- IDE: Anaconda, Xcode, Visual Studio

- Framework: Bootstrap, Django
- Text Editor: Vi/Vim, Sublime Text, Atom
- Library: NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Selenium, BeautifulSoup
- Version Control: Git

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Analyst Programmer Integrated Plant Protection Center, Oregon State University**

May 2017 - Present Corvallis, Oregon

- Develop a risk-model web application back-end mechanism to support users nationwide in implementing pest management decisions in agriculture
- Improve daily weather data (from NOAA, MesoWest, etc.) parsing efficiency by utilizing parallel computing techniques (e.g. Multi-thread and Multi-process)
- Setup USPEST.ORG failover mechanism to prevent service offline
- Design new interface of USPEST.ORG by taking advantage of Django, Bootstrap, etc.

## **Computer Teacher** DaTung Senior High School

August 2008 – July 2013 Pingtung, Taiwan

- Managed and maintained a computer laboratory. Duties included PC assembly and troubleshooting, OS and software installation, network configuration (e.g. TCP/IP, DNS, etc.), and FTP server settings
- Designed, organized and conducted courses focusing on Microsoft Office suite, image processing with Corel PhotoImpact, video editing with CyberLink PowerDirector, and programming in Microsoft Visual Basic

### **Dept. of Data Processing Teacher**

August 2007 – July 2008 NengRen Home Economic and Commercial Vocational High School Taipei, Taiwan

Designed, organized and conducted courses focusing on class C technician certification in web design with Microsoft web development tools and class B technician certification in computer software application with Microsoft Office suite

Taught concepts of PC architecture, PC assembling, and Microsoft Visual Basic in the computer information club weekly meeting

### **PROJECTS**

Weather Data Merging

July 2017

Make use of virtual weather data to replace missed or irrational observed data in temperature, dew point, relative humidity, etc. within a climate and weather-based decision support system for agriculture

Particle System
 Utilized OpenMP, OpenCL, and OpenGL to depict phenomena in games or movies such as clouds, dust, fireworks, etc.

• Operating System

September 2015

Implemented a sysfs (Pseudo File System) interface to VMCS (Virtual Machine Control Structure)

## **EDUCATION**

• Master of Engineering in Computer Science GPA: 3.31/4 Oregon State University

2014 – 2016 Corvallis, OR

• Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical and Electronics Engineering National Taiwan Normal University

2001 – 2005 Taipei, Taiwan

### **HONORS & AWARDS**

Certificate of Appreciation – Ministry of National Defense

2007, Taiwan

• Bronze Medal of 1st Kaohsiung Website Expo – *Taiwan School Cyberfair* 

2006. Taiwan